Guide to the Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry Records - Addendum A
Yale University Divinity School Library
Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry Records - Addendum A
1944-2003
RG 107A
Yale University Divinity School Library
13
(31 boxes)
This record group represents a series of addenda to the original archives of the CESCM that were received in 2000. It contains material related to predecessor organizations and administrative files from the CESCM from its inception in 1987 to its dissolution in 2009. The Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry was composed of denominational staff and college/university students from the Christian Church (Disciples of Christ), the Episcopal Church, the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America, and Presbyterian Church (USA), the United Church of Christ, and the United Methodist Church. It became an affiliate member of the World Student Christian Federation in 1995.
Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the CESCM
Biographical / Historical
1987 Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry is formed
1990 Dec 28 - 1991Jan 1 "Celebrate" Conference I in Louisville, Kentucky
1994 Dec 28 - 1995 Jan 1 "Celebrate" Conference II in St. Louis, Missouri
1995 CESCM was affiliated with the WSCF as a member movement, joining student Christian movements from more than 80 countries
1998Dec 30 - 1999 Jan 3 "Celebrate" Conference III in Ridgecrest, North Carolina
2002 Dec - 2003 Jan "Celebrate" Conference IV in Albuquerque, New Mexico
2006 Dec.28-2007 Jan 1 "Celebrate" Conference V in New Orleans
2007 The Council for Higher Education Ministries (CHEM) dissolved as a 501 c 3 not-for-profit corporation in 2007 and its activities merged into the National Council of Churches of Christ in the USA. CHEM was established in the mid 1990s as an umbrella agency with three work groups: the Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry (CESCM), Higher Education Ministries Arena (HEMA), and United Ministries in Higher Education (UMHE).
2009 CESCM dissolved effective December 31, 2009
Scope and Contents
These records continue and supplement the archives of the CESCM found in Record Group No. 107. They document ecumenical student Christian work in the United States and are valuable for the way in which they complement other archival collections at the Divinity Library. In conjunction with papers of Ruth Harris, Margaret Flory, John R. Mott, Clarence P. Shedd, Robert Wilder, Luther Wishard, Henry Burt Wright and others, as well as the archives of the World Student Christian Federation (WSCF), Student Volunteer Movement, Student Christian Movement in New England, New England Commission for United Ministries in Higher Education, National Campus Ministry Association, YMCA Student Division, United Ministries in Higher Education, the CESCM archives provide a detailed picture of the development of religious work among college and university students in the United States. Documentation of the latter years of the CESCM is also available in the archives of the Council of Higher Education Ministries (YDSL RG 226), which served as an umbrella agency for CESCM and two other organizations involved with student religious work.
Series VII, Clyde Robinson Files, was added in 2010. It contains documentation regarding the formation of the Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry and the CESCM's relation to other ecumenical groups.
Series VIII, Addendum 2011, consists of files of Douglas Fenton and Dennis Landon, denominational administrators who were among the leadership of CESCM in its last period, and contains documentation of the latter years of the CESCM. The CESCM, Higher Education Ministries Arena (HEMA) and United Ministries in Higher Education (UMHE), and their oversight agency, the Council of Higher Education Ministries, were very intertwined and this is reflected in the documentation found here; CESCM's interaction with the WSCF is also documented. Thorough study of this era will require consultation of documentation in this record group in conjunction with that of related archives held at the Yale Divinity Library.
Arrangement
I. Office Files and Correspondence, 1989-2003
II. Organization and Policy Records, 1958-2003
III. Program Files and Records, 1986-2003
IV. Publications, 1944-1999
V. Celebrate Conferences, 1990-2003
VI. Financial Records, 1998-2002
VII. Addendum: Clyde Robinson Files, 1985-1992
VIII Addendum 2011, 1986-2009
Church work with students; College students -- Religious life; Universities and colleges -- Religion; Educators; Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministry
- Office Files and Correspondence, 1989-2003; Series I
  - Correspondence with Yale Archives, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sexual Harassment Policy in USA and Canada, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Office Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Mailing Lists, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Office Correspondence with WSCF, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - 1994 Press Releases (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mailing Lists, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Office Letters, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - E-mail Office Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Office Correspondence with WSCF, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Office Resources, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mailing Addresses, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Office Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mailings, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Office Correspondence by e-mail, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Responsibility Statement and Passports for Group Travel, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Office Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Student Roster, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Office Correspondence by e-mail, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sexual Harassment Charge at 2002 meeting in Canada, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Staff Performance Appraisal, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Retreat Centers in NY State and NYC (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Retreat Centers in Eastern USA except NY State (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Retreat Centers in Mid-West and Western USA (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Organization and Policy Records, 1958-2003; Series II
  - Documents of Formation of NSCF and other Information, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Notes from WSCF meeting, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Planning Committee for New Directions, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Structure of WSCF, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Statement of Purpose and History, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Notes from WSCF meeting in USA, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Consultation Report, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Planning Committee Minutes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Partners meeting Minutes, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - History Project: WSCF Development of CESCM, 1991-92 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Relationship with WSCF, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Affiliated Movements, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Notes on Ecumenical gathering of Youth, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Notes on SCM Conference, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Notes from WSCF meeting on Solidarity with Cuba, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Partners Meeting, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Staff Meeting Reports, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Partners Meeting Minutes, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Notes on European Student Chaplains Conference, 1993-2000 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Interim Executive Secretary, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Partners Meeting, Feb 1994 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Trustees Meeting, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Partners Meeting, Nov 1994 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive Meeting, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Trustees in France, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Notes from WSCF meeting/General Assembly, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Executive Secretary Search, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Notes from WSCF meeting-North American Consultation, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Notes from WSCF meeting-travel to USA, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive meeting, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Partners Meeting Handouts, Mar 1995 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Partners Meeting, Mar 1995 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Partners Meeting, Oct 1995 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Notes from WSCF Women's Centennial Assembly, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Trustees in USA, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Notes from WSCF General Assembly Workbook, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Administration Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Inter-Denominational Outreach, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Friends and Trustees of WSCF, 1995-2002 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Partners Meeting, Mar 1996 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Partners Meeting, Nov 1996 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive and Staff Meetings, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Administration Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Trustees in USA meeting, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Notes from WSCF Latin American Region, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Partners Meeting, Mar 1997 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Notes from WSCF Asian Pacific Regional Meeting, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Partners meeting, Nov 1997 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting-Travel Plans, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive Meeting, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Notes and Minutes from WSCF Meeting, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Partners Meeting Minutes, 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Administration Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Trustees in USA Meeting, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Partners Meeting Reports, Mar 1998 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive Meeting, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Partners Meeting, Nov 1998 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Partners Meeting Agenda, Nov 1998 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Notes from WSCF Special Friends Meeting, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive Meeting, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Notes from WSCF European Committee Meeting, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting-Consultation, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Administration Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Trustees in USA, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Partners Meeting, Mar 1999 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting-General Assembly, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Notes from WSCF Meeting, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Notes from WSCF Executive Meeting, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Partners Meeting, Nov 1999 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Partners Meeting, Nov 2000 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Partners Meeting Minutes, 2000-2003 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Notes from SCM Canada Meeting, 2001-2003 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Address Lists, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 103)
- Program Files and Records, 1986-2003; Series III
  - Denominational Programs, 1986-1992 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Proposed Programs, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Notes from WSCF leadership training, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Denominational Responses to 'Re-Imagining Conference", 1994 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - National Ecumenical Christian Student Gathering, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Inter-denominational Programs, 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 109-110)
  - Women's Program Ministries, 1994-1997 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Workshop on Christian Unity, 1994-1998 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Universal Day of Prayer, 1994-1999 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Report on CCA-WSCF Joint Programs, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Program Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Inter-denominational Programs, 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Programs with SCM in Canada, 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Lingua Franca Trip, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Volunteers, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - STEP Team: Projects and Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Young Adult ministry Team, 1995-1998 (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Denominational Events: Notes on Moravian Convention, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Campus Ministry, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Orientation, 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Volunteer Opportunities, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Ecumenical Young Women United, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Denominational Programs and Events, 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 127-128)
  - Joint Programs with SCM of Canada, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Denominational Programs and Events-Methodist Forum, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Travel Seminar to Cuba, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Travel Seminar to Cuba-Orientation, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Global Ministries, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Denominational Programs and Events, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - Lingua Franca, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Project Vision, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Project Hope, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Denominational Programs and Events, 2001-2003 (Box 14, Folder 138)
- Publications, 1944-1999; Series IV
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes publications of predecessor and related organizations.
  - USCC Manuals and various publications, 1944-1958 (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Communique by USCC, 1948-1965 (Box 14, Folder 140-141)
  - Communique by USCC, 1956-1965 (Box 14, Folder 141)
  - Various Publications, 1960's (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - Publications of WSCF, 1970-1980's (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - Jubilee Publication-Called to Dream, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Terrorism, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Church in Covenant, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - Seminarians Resources, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Celebrate Many Gifts, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 148)
  - The Next 45 Years, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 149)
  - Praxis, 1990-1999 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Publication Guide, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 151)
  - Mission Opportunities, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 152)
  - WSCF Annual Reports, 1992-1997 (Box 15, Folder 153)
  - FIM History, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 154)
  - Sara y Abraham by Schwantes, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 155)
  - The F-Word and No More Mr. Nice Guy-by SCM, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 156)
  - All Things New, 1993-1999 (Box 15, Folder 157)
  - Movement, 1993-1999 (Box 15, Folder 158)
  - Accion Eccumenica, 1993,95,98 (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - Christian Fundamentalism Today, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 160)
  - Dailogo Entre Culto y Cultura, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 161)
  - WSCF Programs, 1993, 95, 96, 98 (Box 16, Folder 162)
  - Animal Crackers, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 163)
  - Federation News WSCF, 1994-1999 (Box 16, Folder 164)
  - Universal Day of Prayer, 1994-1999 (Box 16, Folder 165)
  - Break through, 1994-1999 (Box 16, Folder 166)
  - Journal of Ecumenical Studies: vol 32, # 3, 4, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 167)
  - WSCF Journal, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 168)
  - Many Ways of Walking in the Way, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - Doing Theology in the USA, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - To Build and Plant-WSCF Program Dossier 1, 2, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - WSCF History Series 5, 7, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - Video-WSCF General Assembly and History of WSCFs, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - WSCF Grey Book, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Comunidad de Anticipacion, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - WSCF Consultation on Education, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - Memory and Hope-WSCF General Assembly minutes, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Frontier Internship in Mission, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Plumb line, 1995-1997 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Presbyterian Publication, 1995-1997 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - National Camps Ministry Newsletter, 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Advent and Lent Guides, 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - New Zealand SCM, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - La Ceramica..., 1996 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - Reformed World Vol. 46, No. 1, Mar 1996 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - World SCF Directory, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Medicina Tradicianal, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Religious Manager Conference, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - The Common Thread, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - The Meeting Ground - Presbyterian, 1996-1999 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - From Past to Future, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - WSCF Europe-Newsletter and Mozaik, 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - WSCF African Religion, 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - University Chaplains Newsletter, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - AKONGA, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 196)
  - Ecumenica, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 197)
  - Fidel Castro Speaks, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - The Christian Century, 1989-1991 (Box 18, Folder 199)
  - AIKYATHA-SCM of India, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - Bulletin of Armenian Christian Students, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - History Series No. 6-Towards a Women's History, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 202)
- Celebrate Conferences, 1990-2003; Series V
  For Celebrate IV and V, see also the archives of the Council of Higher Education Ministries Archives, YDSL RG 226.
  - Celebrate I
    - Planning Meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 203)
    - Budget, 1990-1991 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 204)
    - WSCF Guests, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 205)
    - Program, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 206)
    - Planning And Coordinating, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 207)
    - Registration, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 208)
    - Planning Committee Members, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 209)
    - Invitation to Conference, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 210)
    - Fair Share Conference, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 211)
    - Contracts for Conference Administrator, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 212)
  - Celebrate II
    - Planning Committee Correspondence, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 213)
    - Planning Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 214)
    - Tax Exempt Status, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 215)
    - Conference Reports and Participants, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 216)
    - Harassment Policy, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 217)
    - Art Work, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 218)
    - Welcome, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 219)
    - Vender Contracts, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 220)
    - International Participants, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 221)
    - Hospitality Information, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 222)
    - International Participants, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 223)
    - Orientation, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 224)
    - Reports and Budget, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 225)
    - Press Releases, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 226)
    - Back 2 Faith: T-shirt, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 227)
    - Airline Information, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 228)
    - Service Contracts, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 229)
    - Insurance, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 230)
    - Database Information, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 231)
    - Planning Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 232)
    - Planning Committee meetings in 1993, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 233)
    - Planning Committee meetings in 1994, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 234)
    - St. Louis Hotels, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 235)
    - Registration, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 236)
    - Convention Center, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 237)
    - Convention Resume, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 238)
    - Episcopal Pre Convention Meeting, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 239)
    - Convention Information, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 240)
    - Program Booklet Formation, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 241)
    - Planning Worship, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 242)
    - Post-event Reflections, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 243)
    - Evaluation Responses, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 244)
    - Publicity, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 245)
  - Celebrate III
    - Applications for Student Council Administrator, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 246)
    - Planning Committee, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 247)
    - Partners Meeting Minutes and Report about Convention, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 248)
    - Workshop Leaders Evaluation, 1998-1999 (Box 23, Folder 249)
    - Workshop Information, 1998-1999 (Box 23, Folder 250)
    - Workshop Proposals, 1998-1999 (Box 23, Folder 251)
    - Workshop Scheduling, 1998-1999 (Box 23, Folder 252)
    - Workshop Evaluations and Notes, 1998-1999 (Box 23, Folder 253)
    - Team Meetings, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 254)
    - General Information, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 255)
    - Post-Committee Report, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 256)
    - Registration and Guests, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 257)
    - Guest Orientation, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 258)
    - Financial Records and Budget, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 259)
    - Program of Celebrate III, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 260)
    - Ridgecrest Convention Center, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 261)
    - International Guest Committee Report, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 262)
  - Celebrate IV
    - Preliminary Site, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 263)
    - Albuquerque Convention Center, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 264)
    - Schedule and Events, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 265)
    - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 266)
    - Speakers, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 267)
    - Workshops, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 268)
    - Workshop Proposals, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 269)
    - Convention and Visitors Bureau, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 270)
    - Fall Meeting, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 271)
    - Registration, 2002-2003 (Box 26, Folder 272)
    - Proposal for Convention, 2002-2003 (Box 26, Folder 273)
    - Convention Services, 2002-2003 (Box 26, Folder 274)
    - Exhibits, 2002-2003 (Box 26, Folder 275)
- Financial Records, 1988-2002; Series VI
  - Trustees Fundraising, 1988-1993 (Box 26, Folder 276)
  - Centennial Fund, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 277)
  - Office Expenses, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 278)
  - Budget, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 279)
  - Centennial Fund, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 280)
  - Statement and by-laws, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 281)
  - Budget, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 282)
  - Computer purchases, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 283)
  - GBGM Grant, 1996-1999 (Box 27, Folder 284)
  - Operating Funds, 1999-2002 (Box 27, Folder 285)
  - Telephone Service, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 286)
- Addendum: Clyde Robinson Files, 1985-1991; Series VII
  Clyde Robinson worked for United Ministries in Higher Education and was involved in the formation of the CESCM. Documents in this series describe the development of the CESCM and its relations with other ecumenical groups. They complement and may duplicate materials found in Series II.
  - National Council of Churches of Christ Education in Society (NCCC-ES) program and projects; includes letters to/from Clyde Robinson, United Ministries in Education (UME), re. church-related ministry in higher education and sharing resources, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Letters re. National Ecumenical Student Christian Council (NESCM) Leadership Development Conference including World Student Christian Federation (WSCF), Student Christian Movement (SCM) and others; staffing and financial reports, NCCC Education in Society program committee meeting, 1986 Feb-Jul (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Letters and reports, incl. UME, NESCC re. budgets, building relations between student Christian movements and ministry to young adults, 1986 Aug-Sep (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - NESCC/Campus Ministry meeting, minutes and follow-up letters, 1986 Oct (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Report on the emerging student Christian movement in the U.S., stressing ecumenism, 1986 Nov (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and reports - Campus Ministry /Global Mission/ WSCF North America meeting, 1986 Dec (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Incl. re. SCM Consortium position description for Gayla Spicknall; announcement of New Directions for the U.S. ecumenical SCM, 1987 Jan (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Announcing New Directions for US. SCM at Campus Ministry/ Global Mission / WSCF NA meeting; minutes, election of steering committee; NESCC no longer a functioning organization, 1987 Feb (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of WSCF NA Partners Consultation; minutes of Steering Committee of CESCM (formerly known as SCM Consortium); financial report, 1987 Mar (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - NCCC-ES minutes of program committee; financial reports for NCCC-ES and CESCM, 1987 Apr-May (Box 28, Folder 10)